<system>
  <title>ReasonBase</title>
  <slogan>
  </slogan>
  <short-description>
    Reasoned debate with formal semantics
  </short-description>
  <medium-description>
    A system for representing arguments according to precise formal
    semantics, promoting reasoned debate and rapid knowledge
    formation.  This gives an operationalist scientific basis to
    discussions, reducing them to syntactic operations.  This
    eliminates large classes of debate tactics and generally informs
    decisions which will improve objective conditions.
  </medium-description>
  <long-description>
    <p>
      How many  times has it been  that arguments have  hinged on tiny
      oversights?  The  process of  reasoning, the dialectic  is good,
      but armchair philosophy is  an indulgence to argue unsoundly and
      socially, as a game.  Even  the excuse that it improves rhetoric
      skills is misleading, as it  corrupts them more than it improves
      them.
    </p>
    <p>
      Anyone  who  is  seriously  interested  in  improving  objective
      conditions,  and  therefore  in  understanding  the  truth,  and
      therefore in conducting arguments by proof should be thrilled by
      the prospect of formalizing the semantics of everyday arguments,
      discussions and questions.  This is  after all the result of the
      greatest  achievements  in  logic  of  the 20th  century  -  the
      formalization, via the reduction to syntactic operations, of the
      proof  and  truth  predicates.   Furthermore, we  now  have  the
      relative  ability  to  implement  such a  system,  by  extending
      currently  existing  software   systems.   Accordingly,  we  can
      collectively  engage in  a  large analytical  effort proving  or
      refuting  certain key  questions, with  a complete  and formally
      verified proof.
    </p>
    <p>
      We  can  eliminate  an  entire  class of  problems  by  reducing
      arguments  to formally verifiable  statements.  In  other words,
      there can  be no  more disputes because  people simply  agree to
      which ever  axioms they  want.  What you  take as  axiomatic is,
      when the axioms are independent of ReasonBase's theories, highly
      subjective, but  certain axiomatizations cannot be  held as they
      are provably inconsistent.
    </p>
    <p>
      ReasonBase grows  because people  take pride in  forming correct
      arguments  about topics  they  are interested  in.   In fact,  a
      "Socratic"  measure  should  be   created  to  reward  the  most
      intellectually   capable  of   these   individuals.   Therefore,
      ReasonBase can be expected to grow rapidly.
    </p>
    <p>
      An essential feature  of ReasonBase is the alignment  of text to
      axioms - facilitating the rapid formalization of written subject
      matter.   This benefits  from  the same  tools  as the  Textbook
      Knowledge Formation project.
    </p>
    <p>
      Thankfully, the work has in large part been accomplished.  There
      are  numerous  projects  that  when combined  will  produce  the
      desired capabilities.  The OpenCyc project has done exactly what
      we purport  to do, they  have assembled a team  of knowledgeable
      philosophers,  logicians, mathematics, programmers,  and subject
      matter experts,  and constructed  exactly such a  project.  This
      will  thus give us  a strong  foundation to  get started  on the
      process of completely formalizing existing arguments.
    </p>
    <p>
      Not  only   will  people   cease  to  argue   about  meaningless
      misunderstandings once we have  a formal basis for argument, but
      the knowledge inherent in the system can then be applied towards
      automatically reasoning  towards solutions in  other cases, thus
      creating intelligent software as an automatic b
      y product.
    </p>
    <p>
      Interestingly, it also necessarily finds use in counter-rhetoric
      applications, to both identify carefully planted assumptions and
      methods  and  to  utilize   them  to  expedite  the  process  of
      acquainting people with the truth and to help them satisfy their
      goals, in the sense mentioned in Aristotle s Rhetoric:
    </p>
    <p>
      <em>
	Rhetoric is useful (1) because things that are true and things
	that are  just have a  natural tendency to prevail  over their
	opposites, so  that if  the decisions of  judges are  not what
	they  ought to  be, the  defeat must  be due  to  the speakers
	themselves, and they must be blamed accordingly. Moreover, (2)
	before some audiences not  even the possession of the exactest
	knowledge  will  make it  easy  for  what  we say  to  produce
	conviction.   For   argument   based  on   knowledge   implies
	instruction,   and   there   are   people  whom   one   cannot
	instruct. Here, then, we must  use, as our modes of persuasion
	and argument,  notions possessed by everybody,  as we observed
	in the  Topics when dealing with  the way to  handle a popular
	audience. Further,  (3) we must be able  to employ persuasion,
	just as strict reasoning can be employed, on opposite sides of
	a question, not in order that  we may in practice employ it in
	both ways (for we must not make people believe what is wrong),
	but in order  that we may see clearly what  the facts are, and
	that, if  another man argues unfairly,  we on our  part may be
	able  to confute  him. No  other  of the  arts draws  opposite
	conclusions: dialectic and rhetoric  alone do this. Both these
	arts draw opposite  conclusions impartially. Nevertheless, the
	underlying facts  do not lend  themselves equally well  to the
	contrary views. No;  things that are true and  things that are
	better  are, by  their  nature, practically  always easier  to
	prove and  easier to  believe in. Again,  (4) it is  absurd to
	hold that a man ought to  be ashamed of being unable to defend
	himself  with his  limbs, but  not of  being unable  to defend
	himself  with speech  and  reason, when  the  use of  rational
	speech is  more distinctive of a  human being than  the use of
	his limbs. And if it be  objected that one who uses such power
	of speech unjustly might do great harm, that is a charge which
	may be made  in common against all good  things except virtue,
	and  above all  against the  things that  are most  useful, as
	strength, health,  wealth, generalship.  A man can  confer the
	greatest of benefits by a  right use of these, and inflict the
	greatest of injuries by using them wrongly.
      </em>
    </p>
    <p>
      It  becomes easy to  work on  Reasonbase.  We  will use  CELT to
      bootstrap our natural language to logic translation service.  We
      will then use  Vampire as our theorem prover.
    </p>
  </long-description>
  <misc>
  </misc>
</system>
